<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Zhymabek Roman's blog site Blog</title>
        <link>https://zhymabekroman.github.io/blog/posts</link>
        <description>Zhymabek Roman's blog site Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[List of the essential applications that you need to have]]></title>
            <link>https://zhymabekroman.github.io/blog/posts/must-have-applications</link>
            <guid>must-have-applications</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[These are my recommended must-have applications that you should try to use (at least). Sure, tastes differ, but these apps cover most of my needs. I preffer to use FOS application, and I strive to achieve this in every way possible.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>These are my recommended must-have applications that you should try to use (at least). Sure, tastes differ, but these apps cover most of my needs. I preffer to use FOS application, and I strive to achieve this in every way possible.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="linux">Linux<a class="hash-link" href="#linux" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="gui">GUI<a class="hash-link" href="#gui" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>I have never used any other distros than Debian and Ubuntu. So I prefer to use Debian with KDE, not snaped Ubuntu. KDE is the best DE I've ever been seen in this Linux DE jungles lol :)</p><ol><li>WPS Office - a full-featured alternative to Microsoft Office, including word processing, spreadsheets, presentations, PDF conversion and more. For me Libre Office is also good, but sometimes it's not correctly opens some documents, and UI is too old for new generation peoples :)</li><li>Telegram - a freeware (almost), cross-platform, cloud-based instant messaging, video and audio calling messenger.</li><li>Sublime Text - a shareware cross-platform source code editor. It natively supports many programming languages and markup languages. As an alternative - Kate.</li><li>Microsoft Edge - Chromium based browser from Microsoft. I think I need to switch to a Chromium.</li><li>Obsidian - second brain of my entire life.</li><li>Puffin Browser - Chromium based browser. Use cloud server to render pages. Good solution for low end PC and laptop devices. Installation guide for Linux - <a href="https://github.com/ZhymabekRoman/Puffin-Browser-on-Linux" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/ZhymabekRoman/Puffin-Browser-on-Linux</a></li></ol><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="cli">CLI<a class="hash-link" href="#cli" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ol><li>fish - best alternative for bash, sometimes it's unusual but convenient. As an alternative I've tried using ZSH with OhMyZSH configs, but for me it's slow.</li><li>vim - best IDE in the world! My config file - <a href="https://github.com/ZhymabekRoman/MyVIM" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/ZhymabekRoman/MyVIM</a>. As an alternative I've tried to using NeoVIM, but for me it's not convenient.</li><li>NextDNS - DNS with ad blocker functionality.</li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="android">Android<a class="hash-link" href="#android" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ol><li>Termux - GNU utils on your Android smartphone. Free and Open Source.</li><li>MT Manager - file manager with APK modification toolkits. As an alternative I can recommend MiXplorer.</li><li>TickTick - may be best convenient task manager I've ever been seen.</li><li>Nova Launcher - lightweight launcher for Android.</li><li>Bitwarden - FOS password manager.</li><li>Apktool M - multi-functional APK modification toolkit application.</li><li>WPS Office - one application for all Office formats, not like a Microsoft Office with 10000+ app for every format and functionality, and without Windows register inside application (yeah, disk space leak).</li><li>Telegram for primary account and Telegraher for other accounts.</li><li>WhatsApp - a big "backdoor" application to your smartphone. I use modification from Fouad.</li><li>Spotify and Dezeer - as a mussician I need hight quality music, so I preffer to use music services instead some sort of shit like VK music.</li><li>As borwser I preffer to use Bromite WebView with Via browser, or Kiwi Browser.</li><li>Google Keep Note - light weight notepad application for small thoughts. There may be better notepads there, but for me this is enough.</li><li>Obsidian - second brain of my entire life.</li><li>NextDNS - DNS with ad blocker functionality. Use System DOH setting if you have a newer (&gt;10) Android version.</li><li>Easy Voice Recorder - best multi-functional application for audio recordings.</li><li>QuickEdit - simple text editor.</li><li>NeoBackup - application backup toolkit. Free and Open Source.</li></ol>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>applications</category>
            <category>linux</category>
            <category>android</category>
            <category>must-have</category>
            <category>essential</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>