<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://zhymabekroman.github.io/blog/posts</id>
    <title>Zhymabek Roman's blog site Blog</title>
    <updated>2023-04-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://zhymabekroman.github.io/blog/posts"/>
    <subtitle>Zhymabek Roman's blog site Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://zhymabekroman.github.io/blog/img/profile.png</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Must have browser extensions]]></title>
        <id>must-have-browser-extensions</id>
        <link href="https://zhymabekroman.github.io/blog/posts/must-have-browser-extensions"/>
        <updated>2023-04-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My must have browser extensions]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My must have browser extensions</p><ol><li>uBlock Origin - An efficient blocker.</li><li>Bitwarden - FOS password manager.</li><li>Tampermonkey - userscript manager. My userscripts list: <a href="https://greasyfork.org/scripts/36788-spotify-web-copy-track-info-to-clipboard/code/Spotify%20Web%20-%20Copy%20track%20info%20to%20clipboard.user.js" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spotify Web - Copy track info to clipboard</a> and <a href="https://greasyfork.org/scripts/19993-ru-adlist-js-fixes/code/RU%20AdList%20JS%20Fixes.user.js" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RU AdList JS Fixes</a></li><li>SmartProxy - best (I have ever seen) proxy manager. I use it with local WARP-cli</li><li>SingleFile - extension that helps to save a complete page as a single file with all page assets.</li><li>Refined GitHub - extension that enhances the user interface and functionality of GitHub.</li><li><a href="https://gitlab.com/magnolia1234/bypass-paywalls-chrome-clean/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bypass Paywalls Clean</a> - access to online publishing platforms without paying for a subscription or a membership.</li><li><a href="https://github.com/anaclumos/bing-chat-for-all-browsers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bing Chat for All Browsers</a> - enables Bing AI in Edge rather browsers.</li><li>Decentraleyes - Local emulation of Content Delivery Networks. Enhances your online privacy.</li><li>Tabliss - A beautiful, customisable New Tab page.</li><li>ClearURLs - Remove tracking elements from URLs.</li></ol>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Zhymabek Roman</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/ZhymabekRoman</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="browser" term="browser"/>
        <category label="chromium" term="chromium"/>
        <category label="firefox" term="firefox"/>
        <category label="extensions" term="extensions"/>
        <category label="must-have" term="must-have"/>
        <category label="essential" term="essential"/>
        <category label="vivaldi" term="vivaldi"/>
        <category label="online" term="online"/>
        <category label="privacy" term="privacy"/>
        <category label="internet" term="internet"/>
        <category label="www" term="www"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[List of the essential applications that you need to have]]></title>
        <id>must-have-applications</id>
        <link href="https://zhymabekroman.github.io/blog/posts/must-have-applications"/>
        <updated>2023-01-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[These are my recommended must-have applications that you should try to use (at least). Sure, tastes differ, but these apps cover most of my needs. I preffer to use FOS application, and I strive to achieve this in every way possible.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>These are my recommended must-have applications that you should try to use (at least). Sure, tastes differ, but these apps cover most of my needs. I preffer to use FOS application, and I strive to achieve this in every way possible.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="linux">Linux<a class="hash-link" href="#linux" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="gui">GUI<a class="hash-link" href="#gui" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>I prefer to use Debian or Manjaro with KDE. KDE is the best DE I've ever been seen in this Linux DE jungles lol :)</p><ol><li><a href="https://www.wps.com/office/linux/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">WPS Office</a> - a full-featured alternative to Microsoft Office, including word processing, spreadsheets, presentations, PDF conversion and more. For me Libre Office is also good, but sometimes it's not correctly opens some documents, and UI is too old for new generation peoples :)</li><li>Telegram - a freeware (almost), cross-platform, cloud-based instant messaging, video and audio calling messenger.</li><li>Sublime Text - a shareware cross-platform source code editor. It natively supports many programming languages and markup languages. As an alternative - Kate.</li><li>Chromium - open-source graphical web browser based on the Blink rendering engine.</li><li>Obsidian - second brain of my entire life.</li><li>Puffin Browser - Chromium based browser. Use cloud server to render pages. Good solution for low end PC and laptop devices. Installation guide for Linux - <a href="https://github.com/ZhymabekRoman/Puffin-Browser-on-Linux" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub repo</a></li></ol><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="cli">CLI<a class="hash-link" href="#cli" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ol><li>fish - best alternative for bash, sometimes it's unusual but convenient. Not compatible with POSIX syntax. As an alternative I've tried using ZSH with OhMyZSH configs, but for me it's slow.</li><li>vim - best IDE in the world! My config file - <a href="https://github.com/ZhymabekRoman/MyVIM" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub repo</a>. As an alternative I've tried to using NeoVIM, but for me it's not convenient.</li><li>NextDNS - DNS with ad blocker functionality.</li><li><a href="https://developers.cloudflare.com/warp-client/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">WARP</a> - mini "VPN" from Cloudflare.</li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="android">Android<a class="hash-link" href="#android" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ol><li>Termux - GNU utils on your Android smartphone. Free and Open Source.</li><li>MT Manager - file manager with APK modification toolkits. As an alternative I can recommend MiXplorer.</li><li>TickTick - may be best convenient task manager I've ever been seen.</li><li>Nova Launcher - lightweight launcher for Android.</li><li>Bitwarden - FOS password manager.</li><li>Apktool M - multi-functional APK modification toolkit application.</li><li>WPS Office - one application for all Office formats, not like a Microsoft Office with 10000+ app for every format and functionality, and without Windows register inside application (yeah, disk space leak).</li><li>Telegram for primary account and Telegraher for other accounts.</li><li>WhatsApp - a big "backdoor" application to your smartphone. I use modification from <a href="http://down.fouadmods.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Fouad</a>.</li><li>Spotify and Dezeer - as a mussician I need hight quality music, so I preffer to use music services instead some sort of shit like VK or Yandex music.</li><li>As borwser I preffer to use Bromite WebView with Via browser, or Kiwi Browser.</li><li>Google Keep Note - light weight notepad application for small thoughts. There may be better notepads there, but for me this is enough.</li><li>Obsidian - second brain of my entire life.</li><li>NextDNS - DNS with ad blocker functionality. Use System DOH setting if you have a newer (=&gt;10) Android version.</li><li>Easy Voice Recorder - best multi-functional application for audio recordings.</li><li>QuickEdit - simple but powerfull text editor.</li><li>NeoBackup - application backup toolkit. Free and Open Source.</li><li>Yandex Keyboard - multi-functional and convenient keyboard.</li><li>As proxy (VPN) I prefer to use:
SagerNet - all-in-one proxy manager.
ProtonVPN - privacy orintied VPN service from Switzerland (yeah, we known it - <a href="https://www.rt.com/news/534130-swiss-protonmail-french-climate/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.rt.com/news/534130-swiss-protonmail-french-climate/</a>).
1.1.1 (aka WARP) - mini "VPN" from Cloudflare.</li><li>DVGet - lightweight download manager. I prefer to use lightweight version - <a href="https://4pda.to/forum/index.php?showtopic=280941&amp;view=findpost&amp;p=117089212" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">4pda</a></li></ol>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Zhymabek Roman</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/ZhymabekRoman</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="applications" term="applications"/>
        <category label="linux" term="linux"/>
        <category label="android" term="android"/>
        <category label="must-have" term="must-have"/>
        <category label="essential" term="essential"/>
    </entry>
</feed>